Finding Aid for West Side United Methodist Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.) Records, 1846-2000
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Photographs and Postcard File
  - Blooper Ball Team 1964 (Box 13)
  - Boards and Commissions (Box 13)
  - Boy Scout God and Country Award 1970 (Box 13)
  - Building Committee Visits a Grand Rapids Church 1951 (Box 13)
  - Ceremony Honoring Rev. Nancy Woycik (Box 13)
  - Children and Youth Choirs (Box 14)
  - Choir (Box 14)
  - Christmas Decorations (Box 14)
  - Church and Education Buildings Connecting Addition
    - Groundbreaking Ceremony August 1987 (Box 14)
    - Construction 1987-1988, 4 folders (Box 14)
    - Dedication October 1988 (Box 14)
  - Church Entrance 1992 (Box 14)
  - Church Exterior (Box 14)
  - Church Exterior at Night (Box 14)
  - Church Services (Box 14)
  - Church Staff (Box 14)
  - Coffee Hour (Box 14)
  - Confirmation Classes (Box 14)
  - Construction of the Seventh Street Church (Box 14)
  - Couples Club (Box 14)
  - Covenant Players (Box 14)
  - Division Street Church (Box 14)
  - Easter Breakfast (Box 14)
  - Education Building Consecration 1959 (Box 14)
  - Education Building Ground Breaking 1958 (Box 14)
  - Esslinger Family (Box 14)
  - Foreign Exchange Students 1960-1961 (Box 14)
  - Graduation Sunday (Box 14)
  - Greve Family (Box 14)
  - Home Tour 1996 (Box 14)
  - Honoring Choir Director Carroll Hart and Family 1993 (Box 14)
  - Ice Cream Socials (Box 14)
  - Jefferson Street Church (building and activities) (Box 14)
  - Judson Collins Camp 1960 (Box 14)
  - Lenten Programs (Box 14)
  - Mad Hatters 1994 (Box 14)
  - Maitland Family 1963 (Box 14)
  - Membership Classes (Box 14)
  - Men's Breakfast Club 1974 (Box 14)
  - Methodist Men (Box 14)
  - Ministers 1848-1995, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Model of Addition Joining Church and Education Building (Box 14)
  - Mortgage Burning Ceremony 1958 (Box 14)
  - Mother-Daughter Banquets (Box 14)
  - Motion Picture Film 1951-1952 (Box 14)
  - New Member Receptions (Box 14)
  - Outdoor Service at Site of New Church 1950 (Box 14)
  - Parsonage undated (Box 15)
  - Peter Pan Nursery 1977 (Box 15)
  - Planting Tree Honoring Rev. Nancy Woycik (Box 15)
  - Prayer Retreat 1964 (Box 15)
  - Progressive Dinners (Box 15)
  - Sanctuary (Box 15)
  - Schauer Family 1962, 1977 (Box 15)
  - Stained Glass Windows 1971 (Box 15)
  - Sunday School (Box 15)
  - United Methodist Women (Box 15)
  - United Methodist Youth Fellowship (Box 15)
  - Ushers (Box 15)
  - Weddings (Box 15)
  - West Side Members at Albion College 1957 (Box 15)
  - West Siders Activities (Box 15)
  - Winter Weekend 1988 (Box 15)
  - Work Days (Box 15)
  - Post Card--German Methodist Church undated (Box 15)
- Audiotapes
  The Audiotapes series includes audiotapes of the 1951 groundbreaking, 110th anniversary events, and oral history interviews conducted during 140th anniversary celebrations.
  [Digitized audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.]
  - Anniversaries, 110th, 1956, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
    - [Part 1], [06100-SR-21-1-1]; mp3 file; (110 Anniversary Tape 1; Bell-Busching, Very noisy recording, appears to contain news reports and phone conversations.)
    - [Part 1], [06100-SR-21-1-2]; mp3 file; (110 Anniversary Tape 1; Bell-Busching. Unknown speakers discussing missionary work in Chile as well as church work in Gainesville, Florida.)
    - [Part 2], [06100-SR-21-2]; mp3 file; (110 Anniversary Tape 1; Bell-Busching; Silence between 9:25 and 13:50. Recording of a sermon until about 9:25. After 13:50, a speaker discussing an event at the Church.)
  - Anniversaries, 110th, 1956, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
    - [Part 1], [06100-SR-22-1]; mp3 file; (110 Anniversary Tape 2: Benish Fletchhall. Pastor discussing the history of the building and development of the church and the renovation of the basement.)
    - [Part 2], [06100-SR-22-2-1]; mp3 file; (110 Anniversary Tape 2: Benish Fletchhall. Brief invocation on the groundbreaking or consecration of a church.)
    - [Part 2], [06100-SR-22-2-2]; mp3 file; (110 Anniversary Tape 2: Benish Fletchhall. Unknown male speaker discussing renovations and the history of the Church.)
    - [Part 2], [06100-SR-22-2-2]; mp3 file; (110 Anniversary Tape 2: Benish Fletchhall. Unknown male speaker discussing renovations and the history of the Church.)
  - Anniversaries, 110th, 1956, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
    - [Part 1], [06100-SR-23-1]; mp3 file; (Begins with church bells ringing, dictations from multiple Church members who went to West Side United Methodist Church and participated in missionary work in South America during the early 1900s.)
  - Anniversaries, 110th, 1956, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
    - [Part 1], [06100-SR-24-1]; mp3 file; (110 Anniversary; Shilling. Recording of a church service with sermons and hymn singing.)
  - Church Groundbreaking (2 track), 1951, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
    - [Part 1], [06100-SR-25-1-1]; mp3 file; (Church dedication part 2 and 3. Recording of a dedication and discussing of renovations and building on the Church.)
    - [Part 1], [06100-SR-25-1-2]; mp3 file; (Church dedication part 2 and 3; Content is very quiet and appears to be a radio recording of a baseball game.)
    - [Part 2], [06100-SR-25-2]; mp3 file; (Church dedication part 2 and 3. Content difficult to hear, appears to be a sermon or related to the dedication of the West Side United Methodist Church. Some organ music played at 12:00. At 22:10 content switches to a more audible dedication of the Church.)
  - Church Groundbreaking (single track), 1951, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
    - [Part 1], [06100-SR-26-1]; mp3 file; (Dedication I single track. Recording of a sermon and the singing of hymns in the Church.)
  - Church Groundbreaking, 1951, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
    - [Part 1], [06100-SR-27-1]; mp3 file; (Groundbreaking; Pentron. Unidentified speaker dedicating the church with a prayer and invocation for the Church.)
    - [Part 2], [06100-SR-27-2-1]; mp3 file; (Groundbreaking; Pentron. Discussion of the new church and speeches from members of the church about Youth Group and Sunday School.)
    - [Part 2], [06100-SR-27-2-2]; mp3 file; (Groundbreaking; Pentron. Silence for the first minute, speaker giving instructions on how to use tape recorder; very distorted.)
    - [Part 2], [06100-SR-27-2-2]; mp3 file; (Groundbreaking; Pentron. Silence for the first minute, speaker giving instructions on how to use tape recorder; very distorted.)
  - Church Groundbreaking, 1951, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
    - [Part 1], [06100-SR-28-1]; mp3 file; (Chorus church dedication. Recording of a dinner or family gathering, no other content.)
  - Easter Service, 1957, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch
    - [Part 1], [06100-SR-29-1]; mp3 file; (Sermon for Easter Service given by male speaker.)
  - Easter Service 1957 (Box 15)
  - Education Building Dedication 1958 (Box 15)
  - Interviews on Church History includes Tillie Bauer, Ken and Pauline Crocker, Frieda Carlson, Gerald and Katherine Dakin, Edwin and Helen Weiss, Florence Simmons, Mary Dersham, Bill Standbridge, and Ida and Ralph Ridenour 1987-1989, 2 folders (Box 15)
- Photographs and Drawings File
  (oversize)
  - Drawings and Blueprints for Proposed Addition Connecting the Church and the (Box 16)
  - Education Building 1968 (Box 16)
  - Photograph of Church Exterior 1950s (Box 16)
  - Photograph of Church Interior 1950s (Box 16)
- Films
  The films include the dedication of the organ in 1948, the construction of the church in 1950-1951, various church events such as baptisms, the choir, dinners in the social hall, and the consecration of the addition in 1988.
  - Church Construction 1951-1952 (Box 17)
  - Dedication of Organ (Jefferson Street Church) 1948 (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous Church Scenes Includes Church Services, Baptisms, Choir, Sunday School, Children's Choir, Social Hall Dinners, Methodist Youth Fellowship Activities, University of Michigan Graduation Ceremony 1950s (Box 17)
- Videotapes
  The videotapes are of a consecration service for an addition to the church building.
  - Consecration Sunday for New Addition October 16, 1988, 2 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 17)